<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse">
  <item type="boardgameexpansion" id="17438">
    <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/thumb/img/Nmy70MjTPtJQL49tExKfkgh1cP8=/fit-in/200x150/pic77761.jpg</thumbnail>
    <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/original/img/N2J4K8mGqOxfShr-m7sm9-xH2fk=/0x0/pic77761.jpg</image>
    <name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Genesis 48: The First Arab-Israeli War"/>
    <name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="GENESIS II   The Arab Israeli Wars"/>
    <description>Genesis 48 is an expansion to the Advanced Squad Leader game system.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;From the game sleeve:&amp;#10;&amp;quot;Genesis 48 tells the story of a war unlike any before or since. Kibbutzniks defending their homes, fighting alongside their wives. Homemade armored cars trundling into battle. Davidka mortar shells exploding with terrifying shrapnel--due to the soft metal used in the underground shops--with unexpectedly deadly results. The 1948 siege of Jerusalem. Numerous, well-equipped but poorly organized Arab armies.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It's all here in Genesis 48 in a well-researched and extensive module presentation. Three sheets of color die-cut counters include 20 troop-types ranging from elite Israeli Palmach soldiers to Moslem Brotherhood conscripts. Israeli Molotov Tank Hunting Heroes. And more. You also receive numerous new vehicles, including 3 types of Israeli Homemade armored cars, Davidka and Parosh mortars, the Marmon Herrington IV, Jewish 'Sandwich Car' APC, and a variety of half-tracks up-armed with small turrets and a variety of armaments. You also receive a 22&amp;quot; x 34&amp;quot; historical map of Old Jerusalem, a color overlay of a kibbutz, three color card-stock play aids and a 32-page VARIANT rulebook full of vehicle and ordnance notes. All of this equipment is provided to use with the Jerusalem Campaign Game and the 15 well-tested scenarios provided.&amp;quot; (Ownership of ASL, Beyond Valor, Hollow Legions, and Croix de Guerre is necessary to play this game).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Second Edition - GENESIS II The Arab Israeli Wars&amp;#10;&amp;#10;From the Publisher:&amp;#10;GENESIS '48 2nd Edition aims to polish every rough edge of its predecessor, while adding value in the form of new counters and situations. Rules such as the &amp;quot;Molotov Tank Hunting Hero&amp;quot; and others have been streamlined. Squad types have been reduced appropriately and redundancy in rules addressing their use edited down. Scenarios continue to use mostly non-desert, daytime situations and are moderate to small in size and play on geomorphic boards. An all new Kibbutz geo board is provided and a separate JERUSALEM '48 historical map-based module is coming with a fully remastered map that utilizes larger hexes than its predecessor. Thus, GENESIS '48 2nd Edition is a 100% geomorphic board product with 16 exciting scenarios and a LARGE COLLECTION of 1000+ of new counters!  In keeping with the CH approach used in the Berlin and Omaha releases successfully, all you'll need to own is your ASLRB and a collection of marker counters. EVERYTHING YOU NEED in terms of color, die-cut counters is provided in GENESIS '48 2nd Edition! Punch it out and play, no more hunting through tray after tray of old counters to get into the action.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
    <yearpublished value="2001"/>
    <minplayers value="2"/>
    <maxplayers value="2"/>
    <poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
      <results numplayers="1">
        <result value="Best" numvotes="0"/>
        <result value="Recommended" numvotes="0"/>
        <result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0"/>
      </results>
      <results numplayers="2">
        <result value="Best" numvotes="0"/>
        <result value="Recommended" numvotes="0"/>
        <result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0"/>
      </results>
      <results numplayers="2+">
        <result value="Best" numvotes="0"/>
        <result value="Recommended" numvotes="0"/>
        <result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0"/>
      </results>
    </poll>
    <playingtime value="0"/>
    <minplaytime value="0"/>
    <maxplaytime value="0"/>
    <minage value="12"/>
    <poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll>
    <poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll>
    <link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game"/>
    <link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame"/>
    <link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II"/>
    <link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hex-and-Counter"/>
    <link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation"/>
    <link type="boardgamefamily" id="62" value="Advanced Squad Leader"/>
    <link type="boardgamefamily" id="10630" value="Country: Israel"/>
    <link type="boardgameexpansion" id="108569" value="Critical Hit! - Volume 6, No. 3"/>
    <link type="boardgameexpansion" id="108571" value="Critical Hit! - Volume 6, No. 4"/>
    <link type="boardgameexpansion" id="243" value="Advanced Squad Leader" inbound="true"/>
    <link type="boardgamedesigner" id="5634" value="Bob O'Connor"/>
    <link type="boardgamepublisher" id="928" value="Critical Hit, Inc."/>
    <statistics page="1">
      <ratings>
        <usersrated value="19"/>
        <average value="7.60526"/>
        <bayesaverage value="0"/>
        <ranks>
          <rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked"/>
          <rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked"/>
        </ranks>
        <stddev value="1.73644"/>
        <median value="0"/>
        <owned value="101"/>
        <trading value="0"/>
        <wanting value="3"/>
        <wishing value="8"/>
        <numcomments value="13"/>
        <numweights value="2"/>
        <averageweight value="3.5"/>
      </ratings>
    </statistics>
  </item>
</items>
