<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse">
  <item type="boardgame" id="66660">
    <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/thumb/img/8uDt46FjwLjCNpubGNhL2f-5Zfw=/fit-in/200x150/pic662957.jpg</thumbnail>
    <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/original/img/HGj-CLnLvx_5_8xDJY1Ebw04Od0=/0x0/pic662957.jpg</image>
    <name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="En Avant!"/>
    <description>En Avant! Tactical Warfare in the Age of Napoleon.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;From the rulebook introduction:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;This system is designed to play out a regimental level battle using 25mm figures in about half an hour or so.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;The main design aims were: a. A game that could be understood and played by non-wargamers, b. A game that was very fast moving, c. A game which rewarded the correct historical tactics.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;In order to meet these, in some ways conflicting, objectives some considerable liberties have been taken with operational detail.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;The main approach has been to make the system incredibly rapid to play - and all the rules can actually be easily memorised by reasonably experienced umpires after just a couple of games.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;Ideally, the game is controlled by someone acting as Game Control (or Umpire) who does not give the rules to the players. This adds some uncertainty play and discouraged player from &amp;lsquo;rules optimising' rather than just getting on ad playing the game.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;In order make it as clear as possible what is going on, the status of the units is shown by labels next to the unit, and players issue orders by using order flashcards. The system does not use dice in combat resolution, which is an approach that is a unusual in most wargaming circles and will come as a bit of shock to conventional gamers.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;This does give a slight chess-like feel to the game, and it does mean that a game which follows the same course will always have the same result. Fortunately, no game survives first contact with the players, and the chances of two games being exactly alike is small.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;Although the rules were tested using 25mm figures, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter what size models you use, and it might look more realistic to put, say, 15mm or 1/300 scale figures on the same sized base.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
    <yearpublished value="2003"/>
    <minplayers value="3"/>
    <maxplayers value="0"/>
    <poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
      <results numplayers="0+">		
				</results>
    </poll>
    <playingtime value="0"/>
    <minplaytime value="0"/>
    <maxplaytime value="0"/>
    <minage value="0"/>
    <poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll>
    <poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll>
    <link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures"/>
    <link type="boardgamecategory" id="1051" value="Napoleonic"/>
    <link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame"/>
    <link type="boardgamedesigner" id="8656" value="Jim Wallman"/>
    <link type="boardgameartist" id="3" value="(Uncredited)"/>
    <link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)"/>
    <statistics page="1">
      <ratings>
        <usersrated value="0"/>
        <average value="0"/>
        <bayesaverage value="0"/>
        <ranks>
          <rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked"/>
          <rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked"/>
        </ranks>
        <stddev value="0"/>
        <median value="0"/>
        <owned value="0"/>
        <trading value="0"/>
        <wanting value="0"/>
        <wishing value="0"/>
        <numcomments value="0"/>
        <numweights value="0"/>
        <averageweight value="0"/>
      </ratings>
    </statistics>
  </item>
</items>
